PRADEEP.C.K



Email: pg.indubai@gmail.com

Address for Communication:

D.No. 18, 1st Main, 2nd Cross Vivekanagar Bangalore– 560001 (Karnataka)

Mobile: +91 9845152337

Personal Data:

Date of Birth 31st Dec 1977

Sex : Male
Nationality : Indian
Passport No. : G 0239248
Marital Status : Married

Languages : English, Hindi,

Urdu, Tamil And Kannada

Areas Of Interests-

Sports: Badminton, Cricket Hobbies: Photography, Traveling, Music.

Career Objective.

Civil Engineer having 11 years of experience. Involved in all aspects of engineering and construction, with solid knowledge of the project development process. Background includes planning, executing project; ensuring project remains within budget; negotiating the contract and assigning responsibility; purchasing equipment and necessary materials.

Achievements.

- Excellency award from Laing O' Rourke.
- > Successfully completed training in safety passport from Laing O' Rourke.
- > Appreciation certificate from safety from Al Naboodah Contracting.
- ➤ Completed the pulse management training from Technip.

Education.

2001 Bachelor of engineering in CIVIL Eng. (University of Mysore, India)

Assets.

- Good Analytical and Logical skills.
- > Excellent communication and interpersonal skills.
- ➤ Highly motivated to work as a team.

Knowledge Areas.

Expertise in : Microsoft Win 98, 00, XP and Win Vista,

Auto Cad

Applications : MS Office, MS Word, MS Excel, Power

Point, Knowledge in Internet.

Slip form: The fastest method of constructing the

Technology vertical Structures.

Work Experience (5 Years in Abroad)

1. Name: Kettaneh Construction Doha, Qatar Designation: Construction Manager (January 2011 to Aug 2012)

Responsibilities:

Project: Plateau Maintenance Project (Oil & gas), Ras Laffan Industrial City, Qatar

- ➤ Managing and directing a team, successful, maintaining the quality of work to ensure strict adherence.
- > Preparation of in site drawings, quality controls of works, preparation of variation statements etc.
- ➤ Cost savings by reducing Re-Work, giving proper guidance to Engineer & foremen's hitting the project within time and budget frame.
- Attend the weekly progress meeting and to review the progress of the site and also to have open discussions for the problems incurring at site to higher level.
- > Proper delivery of right details to the site at the right time in order to ensure an uninterrupted execution of work at site.
- ➤ Liaising with the client and consultant representatives and executing the project in accordance with the approved drawings and method statements

2. Name: Al Naboodah Contracting, Dubai, UAE

Designation: Sr. Engineer (February 2010 to August 2010)

Responsibilities:

Projects: Execution of civil structure construction for Dubai International Airport concourse III expansion project phase III

- > Preparation of in site drawings, quality controls of works, preparation of variation statements etc
- Achieved cost savings by reducing Re work, giving proper guidance to foreman's, hitting the project within and time and budget frame.
- Attended weekly progress meeting and to review the progress of the site and also to have open discussions for the problems incurring at site to higher level.
- > Proper delivery of right details to the site at the right time in order to ensure an uninterrupted execution of work at site.
- Executed rebar detailing from the structural drawings Snagging and De snagging until handed over to the client

3. Name: Laing O' Rourke, Dubai, UAE

Designation: Sr. Civil Site Engineer (April 2008 to February 2010)

Responsibilities:

Projects: Execution of civil structure construction for Dubai International Airport concourse III expansion project phase III, Dubai Aluminum expansion projects in Dubai, Dubai, Jumeira Golf Estates.

- To plan works within the allocated area and make due allowance for programme constraints.
- To ensure that all relevant technical information is available to constriction team at zero defect level
- > To deliver the product as client's requirements and to the company quality standards
- ➤ Planning and executing of the works and to ensure that the site teams requirements for design, delivery etc are satisfied at all times.
- > Provide engineering and technical guidance to operatives, supervision, and management.
- Review Quality Control Plan and Inspection and Test Plan.
- Maintaining the required engineering standards within the appropriate works areas.
- > To, ensure that Method Statements, Risk Assessments, Inspection Test Plans are in place in an appropriate time scale to allow implementation prior to construction works commencing.

4. Name: Belhasa Projects LLC, Dubai, UAE

Designation: Civil Engineer (November 2006 to February 2008)

Responsibilities:

Projects: Capital Towers, Dubai, Atlantis Royal Tower Hotel, Palm Jumeirah, Dubai

Execution of Civil Construction of finishing works in Specialist sub-contractor for swimming pools water features, sports and coatings and other leisure concepts.

- ➤ Co-ordinate with Consultant and Contractor to execute the quality work assigned.
- ➤ Coordinating with the QA/QC and QS to execute scope of work.
- > To ensure that approved drawings and related documents are being used at site.
- ➤ Coordinating Verify that Quality Assurance procedures, schedule of inspection & testing are being implemented.
- Ensure quality of works is maintained at site as per project requirements.
- ➤ Verify that client & Consultant have approved materials received and used at site.
- Ensure that material and equipment are used in accordance with the manufacturer requirements and to good workmanship level.
- Liaise with the Client Executive, Contractors & Sub-contractors.

5. Name: Manasa Consultants, Bangalore, India

Designation: Site engineer (April 2005 to October 2006)

Responsibilities:

Projects: School Building projects in Rural areas from Sarvasikshana Abiyana

- Monitoring progress, preparing as built drawings, bills and payment certificates.
- Carry out QC inspection on the works including steel, concrete, finishes...
- > Supervision and inspection of works according to approved shop drawings and specifications.
- Maintaining QA/QC forms, inspections, measurements, invoicing, follow ups etc.
- Ensure quality of works is maintained at the site as per the project requirements.
- > Provide engineering and technical guidance to supervision and the management.
- ➤ Coordinating with the government officials to get the work as per the programme and schedule.
- 6. Name: G.K Developers, Bangalore, India

Designation: Site Engineer (May 2003 to January 2005)

Responsibilities:

Projects: Apartments, G + 12 Levels, Villas

- ➤ Planning, allotting works to sub-ordinates, checking for the quality and quantity and to motive to the get work done.
- Monitoring progress, preparing as-built drawings, bills and payment certificates.
- > Supervision and inspection of works according to approved shop drawings and specifications.
- > Updated the weekly site progress report, Preparation of labour histogram, Materials & Equipment
- Allocating specified specialized job to sub-contractors.
- > Sub-contractor bill quantity checking and certifying, billing and invoice to the client.
- ➤ Preparing cash flow for the week, work done for the month and up-dated programmed schedule. Coordinating with Consultants for projects approval.
- 7. Name: Chandragiri Constructions, Hassan, India

Designation: Site Engineer (Dec 2001 to April 2003)

Responsibilities:

Projects: Bangalore-Mangalore Railway project, Bridges.

- > Execution of work as per approved drawings.
- > Surveying, line marking and quality maintaining by site supervision.
- ➤ Coordination with consultants and client (Government Engineers).
- > Preparing and getting approvals of as built drawings from local authorities.
- Monthly progress report making to the head office.
- > Preparing cash flow for the week, work done for the month and up-dated programmed schedule.

Skills/Assets:

- Excellent communication skills, both oral and written. Well versed in the use of computer application related to construction field.
- QC inspection of conformity in different construction field <u>Example</u>: Concrete/ steel works, cladding works, water proofing, temporary form works.
- > Appointed as temporary works inspector for projects
- Very good negotiation & strong public relation & team leader.
- > Preparation/ Implementation of ITP, Method statement, engineering design brief, RFI, Check list etc.
- Family with health, safety & environment management etc.
- ➤ Have successfully completed passport certification for health & safety.
- ➤ Well versed in quality management system, ISO 9001
- Major projects Supervision with Clients: Nakheel properties, Dubai civil aviation, Dubal, Indian railways etc.

Main Projects Executed

PROJECTS EXECUTED IN DUBAI, UAE

- ✓ Capital Towers, Dubai Finishing works in floor coating's, water proofing works etc. from November 2006 to January 2007(Belhasa Projects)
- ✓ Atlantis- Royal Towers, Palm jumeirah, Dubai External finishing works, floor finishing works, floor coatings, water proofing works etc. from January 2007 to December 2007 (Belhasa Projects)
- ✓ Jumeirah Golf Estates, Dubai This turnkey project consists of Villas, Commercial Buildings, Club House, Tennis Academy and Golf Academy and a 36 hole golf course at which hosts the world championship, from April 2008 to April 2009 (Laing O' Rourke)
- ✓ **Dubal, Dubai aluminum, Expansion works, Dubai** This project consist of construction cast house, control and electrical sub stations, Bus bar trenches, Cable trenches etc. from April 2009 to August 2009 (**Laing O' Rourke**)
- ✓ **Dubai International Airport Expansion Phase III Concourse III (AX 124 A & D)** Structural works construction, from August 2009 to November 2010 (**Laing O' Rourke**)

PROJECTS EXECUTED IN INDIA

- ✓ Railway Projects, Bangalore- Mangalore railway bridges This project consists of construction of structural works of railway bridges, from December 2001 to April 2003
- ✓ G+12 levels Apartments, Bangalore Project consists of structural and finishing works, from May 2003 to January 2005
- ✓ School building projects from sarva sikshana abiyana Project includes construction school building in rural areas of structural and finishing works, from April 2005 to October 2006